贝克特
Beckett?
兄弟没事吧
Oh, dude.
兄弟你看
Dude.
天啊
科学实验用的小白鼠吗
Aw. Science project?
不  这是只宠物鼠
No, it's a pet.
打个招呼吧  老爸  他是西奥多
Say hello to Theodore, dad.
我帮阿什利看着的
I'm rat-sitting him for Ashley.
你好哇  西奥多
Hello, theodore.
-您在里面跑的怎么样  -知道吗
- How goes the rat race? - Did you know
一只老鼠的寿命平均只有两到三年
the average life span of a rat is two to three years?
但阿什利都养了它五年了
Ashley's had theodore for five.
而且这是他第一次把他交给别人照顾
And this is the first time he's left him with anyone.
这么放心把心爱的宠物交给你
Trusting you with a treasured pet...
感情又加深了嘛
That's a big step in a relationship.
是啊  我也这么觉得
Yeah, I guess it kind of is.
我得说  这小瘟疫传播者
I must say, the little plague pusher
好像不怎么爱锻炼啊
is not very diligent about his exercise.
不知道为什么
I don't know.
可能是因为它贼溜溜的眼睛吧
I-I think it's just those beady little eyes.
老妈  它是只老鼠
It's a rat, mother.
老鼠眼睛都这么贼溜溜的
They all have beady eyes.
贼眉鼠眼就这么来的
That's where the phrase comes from.
爸  那是给西奥多吃的
Dad, those are for Theodore.
它有一套很详细的餐谱
He has a very specific diet
我得按照餐谱喂它
I'm supposed to follow.
除非他是本
Well, unless he's Ben,
我想他不会有什么异议的
I'm sure he won't hold it against me.
有事找我的话
If anyone needs me,
我去公园了  那有一宗命案
I'll be in the park with a dead body.
本是谁
Who's Ben?
一个电影里面的杀人鼠
Killer rat movie.
我们那个年代的
Before your time.
知道吗  我可以理解把雪貂做宠物养
You know, I understand ferrets as a pet--
养蛇  养蜘蛛  甚至养光溜溜的鼹鼠
snakes, spiders, even a hairless mole.
但是养老鼠
But a rat?
城里的孩子没准还把蟑螂当宠物养呢
Probably kids in this city who keep cockroaches as pets.
很可能
You're probably right.
你养过最奇怪的宠物是什么
What's the strangest pet you've ever had?
你喽  嘿  蕾妮
You. Hey, Lanie.
怎么回事  被人撞了又碾过去了
What's this, a hit-and-run?
也可以这么说
In a manner of speaking.
两个自行车越野赛骑手轧过尸体
Two BMX bikers rode over the body,
然后报的警
then called it in.
但是死亡原因是枪伤
But the cause of death are the gunshot wounds--
胸部中一枪
One to the chest,
背后两枪
and two more in the back.
胸前背后都有枪伤
So he's wounded on both sides?
可能有两个人开火  被他赶上了
Maybe there were two shooters, he was caught in the cross fire?
要回到实验室检验才能知道确切原因
Won't know till I get him back to the lab.
死者身份呢
You got an I.D.?
雷纳德·莱维特  住在皇后区臭氧公园
Leonard Levitt, Ozone park, Queens.
钱包  现金  钥匙都在
Wallet, cash, keys-- everything still here.
-也就是说这不是一场抢劫案  -说的对
- Which means it wasn't theft. - No.
这有个更邪恶的东西
Something much more nefarious.
一翎羽毛
A feather.
交替式纹路  色泽均匀
Alternating stripes, uniform color...
这不是普通的鸽子羽毛
This is no ordinary pigeon feather.
这  这是一只猛禽的羽毛
This... This is from a bird of prey.
卡塞尔  你是想说
So what are you suggesting, Castle,
一只鸟开枪打中他三次吗
that a bird shot him three times?
这可不是普通的鸟
Not just any bird.
这正是凶手杀人留下的特殊标志
This is the calling card of a murderer
而这个凶手  就是"猎鹰杀手"
known only as... The Falcon Killer.
也有可能是没中枪之前
Or maybe before getting shot,
他正弯腰去捡这只羽毛呢
he just bent down and picked up the feather.
看吧  所以你们当不了畅销小说家
See, that's why you'll never be a best-selling novelist.
一点情节构造感都没有
No sense of drama.
对我来说有死尸就已经够了
I find that dead bodies are usually enough.
多谢  蕾妮
Thanks, Lanie.
我们查了死者的相关背景  收获很少
Yo. So we ran background on your vic. It's pretty thin.
他是个纽约市运输部门的工人
He was a New York city transit employee.
在第一一六大街地铁站工作
Worked in the subway out of the 116th street station.
他在市中心上班  住在皇后区
He worked uptown and he lived in queens?
那他去公园做什么
Then what was he doing in the park?
这太不通情理了
That's pretty out of the way.
我们以为他是去找地方
Well, we thought that he was looking to buy
吸毒或者嫖娼  但是这家伙没有吸毒史
some weed or some love, but he has no drug history,
没犯过教唆罪  白的像纸一样
no convictions of solicitations, no nothing.
那他的家人呢
And what about his family?
父母双亡  没结过婚
Both parents are deceased. Guy never married,
没有孩子  就好像他从来没存在过一样
has no children. It's like he barely existed.
真是完美的被害人
Making him the perfect victim.
一个城市职员  性格温和
Mild-mannered city employee
被引诱到树木丛生的地方
lured into a conveniently wooded area,
被猎鹰般的凶手
struck down by a murderer
以迅雷不及掩耳之势击毙
with the speed and cunning of a bird of prey.
别理他  你们去他的住处
Don't ask. You guys go to his apartment.
查查他是怎样一个人
Find out who he is
-看他去公园做什么  -好的
- and what he was doing in the park.  - Right.
尸斑和体温显示死亡时间是
Lividity and temperature puts time of death
晚上五点到七点
between 5:00 and 7:00 pm.
死者手腕断裂
The victim also has a broken wrist.
可能是死后被越野自行车骑手碾压
Could be postmortem from those bmxers
玩花样动作时造成的
playing x games on his corpse.
-枪伤呢  -三处伤口
- What about the gunshot wounds? - All three entry wounds
都是由同一把45口径手枪造成
were made by the same weapon-- a .45.
凶手只有一个
There was only one shooter.
同一个人打中他胸口
So the same person shot him in the front,
又在他背后放了两枪
and then shot him in the back?
我也想不通
Didn't make any sense to me either,
所以我做了几项检测
so I decided to take some measurements.
结果证明  三处伤口深度各不相同
Turns out, the wounds are of different depths.
胸部枪伤十分浅
The one on his chest is very shallow,
证明凶手是在一定距离以外开枪的
indicating the shot came from a distance.
-多远  -150英尺左右[约45米]
- How far? - About 150 feet.
凶手枪法很准嘛
That's quite an accurate shot with a handgun.
我判断凶手有射击经验
Yeah, I'd say your killer had some shooting experience.
但是背后的两处伤口  射程很近
But the next two shots in the back were close range,
大概在6英尺以内[1米8左右]
inside 6 feet, maybe.
也就是说  死者在远距离胸部中枪后
So he got shot in the chest at long range,
-转身想逃跑  -但是他受伤了
- turned around to run... - But he's wounded.
凶手穷追不舍要干掉他
The killer goes after him to finish what he started
在背后又开了两枪
with a double tap to the back.
他不只是被枪杀了
He wasn't just shot.
他是被穷追猛打击杀的
He was hunted down and killed.
但是为什么呢
But why?
哇
Whoa.
这家伙在干什么
What was this guy up to?
不知道
No idea.
-那是什么  -好像是什么计数的东西
- What about that? - Looks like some sort of counter.
你觉得他在计算什么
What do you think he was counting?
不是什么好事
Nothing good.
夜视镜  射弹观测镜
Night vision, spotting scope,
抛物面传声器
parabolic microphone--
都是高级设备啊
Top quality, too.
一个地铁职员用这些做什么
What's a subway worker doing with all this?
搞不懂
I don't know.
不管他在做什么
But whatever he was into,
都和这个公园脱不了干系  看
it had something to do with the park. Look.
这正是发现他尸体的地方
This is right where his body was found.
5:26  和死亡时间差不多
5:26--that's around our time of death.
看起来他在追踪缩写为BHS的
Looks like he was tracking something or someone
什么东西或者什么人
with the initials b.H.S.
而且看起来他是被那人找上了
And it looks like that someone found him.
监视工具  秘密接头
Surveillance equipment, clandestine meetings,
职业杀手
a professional hit--
结合地铁元素  像是在看电影
mix in the subway, and we're looking at
《骑劫地下铁》[惊悚犯罪电影]
"The Taking of Pelham 1-2-3,"
或者更好一点的
or better yet,
《金钱列车》[惊悚犯罪电影]
"Money train."
这里每一个人都有可能是帮凶
Any one of these people could be a secret accomplice.
这正是地铁有爱的地方
That's what I love about the subway.
在这里  每一个人都有一个故事
Down here, everyone's got a story.
看  这就是我们两个不同的地方
See, that's the difference between you and me, Castle.
你把地铁看成是构造你小说对白的地方
You see the subway as a place to pick up dialogue for your novels.
有时也是"投资银行家"
Or the occasional investment banker
前往健身房的必经之路[卡塞尔泡妞手段]
on her way to the gym.
而我  把这里看作是
I, on the other hand, see it as a way of getting
从A点到B点交通手段
from point "A" to point "B."
看来是灯泡雷恩死了啊
So lightbulb Len's dead, huh?
-灯泡雷恩  -对  他负责更换整个纽约的
- Lightbulb Len?  - Yeah, it was his job to change the lightbulbs
地铁和隧道的灯泡
in the stations and tunnels all over New York.
我就知道出事了
I figured something was wrong.
22年了  这是他第一次上班缺勤
It's the first time he's missed work in 22 years.
里维拉先生  雷恩被人发现在公园中枪而死
Mr. Rivera, Len was found shot to death in the park.
知道他为什么会去公园吗
Any idea what he was doing there?
他以换灯泡为生
The guy changed lightbulbs for a living.
你也知道  那样的工作  是不合群的
You know, a job like that, it's not for the social.
我当他的上司都12年了
I mean, in the 12 years I was his supervisor,
我想我们甚至没有私下聊过天
I don't think we ever had one personal conversation.
-不过有个人你们该去问问  -谁
- But you know who you should talk to?  - Who?
桑瑟先生
Mr. Sansone?
亚瑟
Arthur!
抱歉   只是
I'm sorry. It's just...
怎么会有人要枪杀他呢
Why would anybody want to shoot him?
我们正希望您能帮我们解答这个问题呢
Well, we were hoping that you could tell us that.
他是这座城市的无名英雄
Well, the guy was one of the unsung heroes of this city.
他挽救了无数条生命
He saved a lot of lives.
抱歉  我...我还以为他是换灯泡的
I'm sorry. I thought-- I thought he changed lightbulbs.
坏事总是发生在黑暗里的  卡塞尔先生
Bad things happen in darkness, Mr. Castle,
比如昏暗的隧道
Dimly lit tunnels,
黑暗的楼梯井
Darkened stairwells.
如果雷恩在下班前听到有灯泡爆炸了
If Len heard about a blown bulb before shift end,
他会主动留下  利用自己的时间把它修好
He would stay late, on his own time, to fix it.
当然  还有他对阿布·里普施茨的悲剧
And of course, there was his response
所做出的回应
to the Abe Lipschitz tragedy.
1989年
1989...
一个灯泡更换工
An electrocution of a bulb changer
被电死在布莱顿海滩站
at the Brighton Beach station.
这是个断路器开关
This is a circuit interrupter switch.
能切断隧道里的所有电源
Shuts down all of the power inside a tunnel
这样维修电路就很安全了
So that electrical maintenance could be performed safely.
这个东西
Down here...
被称为雷恩之盒
It's called the Lenny box...
因为就是雷恩·莱维特这样的梦想家设计了它
Because it took a visionary like Len Levitt to design it
并迫使高速运输管理局
and force the transit authority
在这个城市的每个站点都安装了一个
to install one in every station in this city.
高科技的工具呢
What about high-tech gear?
雷恩在工作中是否使用过夜视镜
Did Lenny ever use any night vision
或者麦克风之类的东西
or microphones for his work?
没有  怎么了
No. Why?
BHS这几个字母  能让你想到什么吗
How about the initials B.H.S.? Does that mean anything to you?
可能是雷恩密切关注的某个人或某种东西
Maybe someone or something that Len was keeping tabs on.
雷恩·莱维特唯一关注的
The only thing Len Levitt ever kept tabs on
就是他换过的每一个灯泡
was every single bulb he ever changed.
据你所知  他是否有任何敌人
Did he have any enemies that you know of?
想办大事  不结下几个仇人是不可能的
You don't make waves without making a few enemies.
由于雷恩的努力
Because of Len,
现在整个系统正在更新装置
we're in the middle  of a systemwide changeover
要将白炽灯换成节能灯
from incandescent to compact fluorescents.
新技术逐渐入主这里
New technology comes in,
这城市最终会像仓库一样堆满老式灯泡
the city ends up with a warehouse full of old bulbs.
这就让一些生产老式灯泡的人
That makes some guy in a suit at the old bulb factory
非常不爽
very unhappy.
在我看来
You ask me,
是某个公司密谋除掉雷恩的
corporations conspired to take Lenny out.
雷恩之盒
"'Lenny box.'"
这家伙还是个发明家啊
So the guy's an inventor?
很明显  他是个多才多艺的地下工作者
Apparently he was an underground renaissance man.
这就解释了那些电子设备
Guess that explains all the electronics.
还有他公寓里记下的数字
And the counter in his apartment--
是他更换过的所有灯泡的数量
All the lightbulbs he changed.
真的吗  这家伙换过一百多万只灯泡
Seriously, this guy changed over a million lightbulbs?
他是个无名英雄   明白吗
The man was an unsung hero, all right?
-被一些大灯泡干掉了  -大灯泡
- Cut down by the forces of big bulb.  - Big bulb?
灯丝工业中心
The filament-industrial complex.
如果雷恩那个朋友真认为他是被灯泡企业
Lenny's buddy is delusional if he actually thinks
密谋干掉的  那他一定有妄想症
that Lenny was killed by a lightbulb conspiracy.
还不能排除那位地下工作者的说法
Well, I wouldn't dismiss our subterranean friend just yet.
我查看了雷恩的通话记录
I was running through len's phone records,
发现了这通电话
and one jumped out.
他打给纽约市员工举报热线的
The outgoing call to the New York city employee tip line?
如果你要举报同事  就可以打这个热线
It's where you call to rat out your coworkers.
"老鼠"非得用成贬义词么
Must "Rat" always be used in the pejorative?
在中国的生肖里  老鼠是
In the chinese zodiac, the rat is ac--
他举报了什么
What was the tip?
他们换下来的那些白炽灯泡
Well, all those incandescent bulbs they were replacing?
莱维特声称自己有证据证明
Levitt claims that he had evidence his supervisor was
他的上司将它们偷去  并转手在黑市上变卖
stealing them and then reselling them on the black market.
你是说马里奥·里维拉吗
You mean Mario Rivera?
就是他  如果指控成立
The same. The charges pan out,
这人的工作和退休金就都没了
the guy could lose his job and his pension.
还有  在他去高速运输管理局之前
Oh, and get this, before he was in the transit authority,
马里奥曾在海军陆战队服役过八年
Mario was in the marine corps for eight years
还因一流的枪法  得到过武器奖章
where he won a weapons medal for sharpshooting.
翻译：东方  苏小黛  小易  小池  千花  小蛮腰
时间轴：零   后期：瓜瓜   校对：大卫熊   总监：安小七
昨晚五点至七点你人在何处
Where were you last night between 5:00 and 7:00 pm?
-在上班  -我们查过  你4:34就打卡下班了
- Working.  - We checked. You clocked out at 4:34.
你去了59街的B区或D区
You, uh, hop the B or the D down to 59th street.
搭捷运的话只要  多久  十分钟吗
The express only takes, what, ten minutes?
有足够的时间去公园杀死雷恩
Plenty of time to get to the park, kill Len.
我为什么要杀他
Why would I kill len?
因为当他发现了哥斯达黎加的事后
Because he filed a report against you
曾向高运管理局提交了一份指控你的报告
with the transit authority when he found out about Costa Rica.
你们在胡说八道些什么
What the hell are you guys talking about?
这些是你发出去的电子邮件
These are e-mails that were sent from you
发给你在哥斯达黎加的联系人的
to your contact in Costa Rica.
这些是我的私人邮件
These are my private e-mails.
可你是用工作间的电脑发送的
Sent from a workplace computer,
所以我们有权查看
which means we can look.
我只是在考虑去那里度假
So I was thinking about taking a vacation down there.
是啊  喝几杯啤酒
Yeah, drink a few cervezas,
没准儿还在海滩跳跳伞
maybe go parasailing on the beach,
顺便卖几个灯泡给当地人
sell some lightbulbs to some locals.
这个城市就像个大仓库
The city has a warehouse
堆满了老式的白炽灯泡
full of old, incandescent lightbulbs
你认为反正没人注意
that you figured no one would miss,
于是就以20美分一只的价格卖给了
so you sold them to a wholesaler in Costa Rica
你在哥斯达黎加的批发商  加起来就是十万
for 20 cents a pop. That's 100 grand.
可惜有人留意到了
Only someone did miss them.
一个叫做灯泡啥啥的人
Someone with the word "Lightbulb" in his name.
当你发现雷恩知道了你的意图
When you found out Len was on to you,
你意识到自己会同时失去工作和退休金
you realized you could lose your job and your pension.
所以你不能让他带着掌握的证据
You couldn't afford to let him go to the transit authority
去高运管理局举报你
with what he knew.
我没杀人
I didn't kill nobody.
那就解释一下
Well, then why don't you just come clean
昨晚五点至七点你做了些什么吧
with what you did last night between 5:00 and 7:00?
马里奥  杀人犯
The thing about murderers, Mario,
一般都没有可靠的不在场证明
Is they tend to not have solid alibis.
通常是因为案发时他们正在杀人
Generally because they're murdering somebody.
听着
Look...
那些老式灯泡  最终会被销毁
those old lightbulbs were just gonna get destroyed
然后扔到垃圾场去
and end up in a landfill.
我只是帮这个城市解决难题
I was doing the city a favor.
没错  我是赚了点外快  伤着谁了啊
So I make a little extra. So who gets hurt?
我想说  伤着雷恩了
Uh... I'm gonna go with Len.
最后一次机会  马里奥
Last chance, Mario.
下班后  我去了大广场街
After work, went up to the Grand Concourse
去把灯泡打包以便发运
to pack up a shipment of lightbulbs.
昨晚已经发往哥斯达黎加了
They went out to Costa Rica last night.
你们可以去查
You can check.
我在那里
I was there.
谢谢
Thanks.
他说的是实话  雷恩打的那通举报电话
He's telling the truth. Len's call to the tip line?
原来运输局那边
Turns out that the transit cops
上周派人去监视他了
had him under surveillance all last week.
负责跟踪他的人证明他昨晚
His tail has him in the Bronx
在布朗克斯区  跟他说的一样
last night just like he said.
打电话告诉运输局的
Call the transit cops and tell them
-我们刚帮他们结案了  -好
- that we just closed their case for them. - Right.
如果不是灯泡害死了雷恩  那是什么呢
So if lightbulbs didn't get Lenny killed, then what did?
他被杀的时间跟他写下的时间恰好一致
You know, it can't be a coincidence that he was killed
这不可能是巧合
right there at about the same time that he has written down.
还有BHS又代表了什么呢  布朗克斯高中
And what does "B.H.S." Stand for? Bronx high school?
大型立体声音箱
Big honkin' stereo?
-有鞋的男孩  -试试拜伦· H· 辛格
- Boys have shoes?  - Try Byron H. Singer.
我在他公寓里找到的抛物面传声器上
I found a small vendor decal on the side
找到了一小张卖家的贴纸
of the parabolic microphone we found in his apartment,
于是我打电话去问对方是否知道
So I called the vendor to find out if he knew
雷恩为什么要买那仪器
why Len bought the equipment.
结果发现  雷恩根本没买过
Turns out, Len didn't buy it at all.
是两个月前  一个保险公司理赔员买下的
It was purchased two months ago by an insurance actuary
-那人名叫拜伦·H·辛格  -BHS
- named Byron H. Singer.  - B.H.S.!
不好意思
Sorry.
辛格先生  谢谢赶你过来
Mr. Singer, thank you for coming down.
他们说有重要事情
They said it was important.
你认识一个叫雷恩·莱维特的人吗
Do you know a man named Len Levitt?
-那混蛋跟你们说什么了  -他什么也没说
- What did that bastard tell you?  - He didn't tell us anything.
那就好  因为他满口胡言
Good, because he's a liar.
他以为他比我更了解
He thought he knew better than me.
-他一副自大狂的样子  -辛格先生
- He thought he knew better than everybody. - Mr. Singer--
我不在乎他相信与否
I don't care if he didn't believe me.
我不在乎这会很伤他自尊
I don't care how much it hurt him.
我知道自己看到了什么
I know what I saw.
你看到了什么
And what did you see?
它们两个  一起
The two of them, together,
在公园里  像一对情侣鹦鹉
in the park, like a pair of lovebirds.
但他控告我捏造了这事
But he accused me of making the whole thing up.
我说  我为什么要捏造呢
I mean, why would I make something like that up?
任何人都不会
Why would anybody?
辛格先生  你究竟在公园里看见了什么
Mr. Singer, what exactly did you see in the park?
我看得很仔细
I saw enough.
相信我  看到它们时  我都惊呆了
And believe me, I was pretty shocked to see them together.
我必须抢先告诉雷恩
I knew I had to tell Len before somebody else did.
当你告诉雷恩时  他肯定很生气
Len must have been very angry when you told him.
既生气又嫉妒  但我跟踪它们
Very angry and jealous, but I had followed them
并且发现它们秘密巢穴
and found their secret spot.
然后我告诉他在何时何地找到它们
And I told him where and when to find them.
我还借给他一些设备
I even lent him some of my equipment
这样他可以自己监视它们
so he could spy on them himself.
那么雷恩去到公园  他亲眼所见
So Len goes to the park, and he sees for himself.
接着对着他们醋意大发
And then he confronts them in a jealous rage,
然后他们杀了他
and they kill him.
他们干了什么
They do what now?
他们杀了他
They killed him.
红杏出墙的女友和她的情人
The cheating grilfriend and her lover.
你们在说什么
What are you talking about?
你在说什么
你那天晚上在公园里看见了谁
Uh... Who did you see in the park that night?
红尾鹰
The red-tailed hawks.
40年来公园里都没有出现过一对
There haven't been a nesting pair in the park for 40 years.
你是在说鸟
You mean, this is about birds?
不只是鸟  而是红尾鹰
Not just birds. The red-tailed hawks.
雷恩监督中心公园船库的日志
Len oversees the log in the central park boathouse,
所有的观测都被正式记录下来
where all the sightings are officially recorded.
但他拒绝认可我的观测
But he refused to acknowledge my sighting.
所以我告诉他  如果他不相信
So I told him, if he didn't believe me,
他可以自己去公园亲眼看看
he should go out to the park and see for himself.
他们黄昏时分筑巢
They nest at dusk.
辛格先生  你昨晚5点至7点
Mr. Singer, were you in the park yesterday
是否在公园里
between 5:00 and 7:00 p.m.?
通常都在  但昨天我在办公室里工作
Usually I am, but yesterday I was in my office, working.
你的同事可以证实吗
And can any of your colleagues verify that?
我确信可以  但关于红尾鹰
I'm sure they can, but about the hawks--
我希望这正式记录下来
and I want this on the official record--
我绝不会夸大或捏造鸟类观测
I would never exaggerate or fabricate a bird sighting.
真难以置信
It's unthinkable.
它们就在那里
They're there,
是我先看到的
and I saw them first.
我会记在官方记录里
I'm putting that in the official record.
设备  公园  羽毛还有辛格先生
So the equipment, the park, the feather, and B.H.S.--
似乎解释了一切
It looks like we've explained everything.
是的  除了他被杀的原因
Yes, except why he was killed.
早上好  老妈
Morning, mother.
早上好
Morning.
为什么奶奶站在桌上而你趴在地上
So why is gram on the table and why are you on the floor?
爸爸  他不见了
Dad, he's gone.
西奥多吗
Theodore?
我喂他藜麦沙拉和小麦粒时
When I fed him his quinoa salad with wheat berries,
肯定没有关好笼子
I must not have closed the cage door all the way,
现在它不见了  阿什利会恨死我的
and now he's gone, and Ashley's going to hate me.
他不会恨你的  他会理解的
Oh, he's not gonna hate you. He'll understand.
不  他不会  他信任我
No, he won't. He trusted me,
而我让他失望了
and I let him down.
不  你没有
No, not yet, you haven't.
我们会找到他的  有没有找过你房间
We'll find him. Have you looked in your room?
还找了奶奶的房间
And in gram's, too.
如何那东西进了我房间
If that creature entered my room,
我要买一张新床和新衣橱
I'm gonna need a new bed... and wardrobe.
爸爸  如果他跑出去了怎么办  就是外面
Dad, what if he got out? Like "Out" out?
好吧  西奥多是只城里鼠
All right, Theodore is an uptown rat.
他还在这里  要找一只啮齿目动物
He's here someplace. Okay, to find a rodent,
你必须像啮齿目动物那样思考
You have to think like a rodent.
你就是西奥多
You are Theodore.
-你想要什么  -食物
- What do you want?  - Food.
你有个私人主厨  你不饿
Eh, you got a personal chef. You're not hungry.
温暖  我想要呆在温暖安全的地方
Warmth. I'd want to stay warm and safe.
没错  舒适安静的地方
Yeah, a cozy, quiet place, out of the way,
没人踩你的地方
where no one's gonna step on you.
前厅衣橱
Front hall closet.
很好
Nice.
你看见了吗
You see him?
没有  它不在这里
No. He's not here.
他不在这里
He's not here.
什么
What?
你得走了
You need to go.
让你一个人找老鼠
And leave you ratless?
这是我的责任  爸爸  不是你的
It's my responsibility, dad. Not yours.
我会找到他的
I'll find him.
-你确定吗  -是的
- Are you sure?  - Yeah.
好吧  有需要给我打电话吧
All right. You call me... If you need anything.
等等  我要住广场酒店
Just so you know, I'm checking into the Plaza,
你付钱
and you're paying.
卡塞尔  我来了  有什么重要的事
Okay, Castle, I'm here. What was so important?
你第一个线索是
Your first clue is...
晚间的狗狗灵异事件
the curious incident of the dog in the nighttime.
天啊  卡塞尔  我甚至还没喝咖啡
Oh, jeez, Castle. I haven't even had my coffee yet.
谢谢
Thank you.
出自夏洛克·福尔摩斯《银色马》
From the Sherlock Holmes story, "Silver Blaze."
福尔摩斯解开谋杀案是因为未发生之事
Holmes unmasks the murderer because of what didn't happen.
狗没有叫
The dog didn't bark.
他由此知道狗必然认识凶手
That's how he knew the dog must have known the killer.
好吧  是的  我记得这故事
Okay. Yes, I remember the story.
那么最困难的侦查
Then you know that the hardest form of detection
就是寻找非现场证物
is looking for the thing that isn't there.
拜伦说雷恩要去证实红尾鹰的真假
Byron said that Len was going to verify the hawks.
证实就是提供证据  也就是说
Verify, as in "Provide proof," which means...
他应该有一个相机  但我们没找到
He would've had a camera... which we didn't find.
如果他当时在拍摄照片
And if he was taking pictures...
我们应该可以知道他干了些什么
We should be able to figure out what he was up to.
我们在这里发现尸体
We found the body here,
他被最后两枚子弹打中
where he took the last two bullets...
逃离凶手追击
Running away from his killer.
他的手腕断了
He had a broken wrist.
被越野自行车手碾过所致
From the bmx guys riding over his body.
或是从树上摔下导致的
Or he fell from a tree.
这棵树
This tree.
这个坑还很新
There's a fresh divot.
全是鸟类
It's all birds.
红尾鹰
Red-tailed hawks.
看来拜伦·辛格说的是真的
Looks like Byron Singer was telling the truth after all.
没错  提醒我通知"鸟类警察"
Yeah, remind me to notify the bird police.
但我可不认为是鹰杀了他
But I doubt it was the hawks that killed him.
哇哦
Whoa.
灯泡雷恩目击了一宗儿童诱拐案
Lightbulb Len witnessed a child abduction.
他最后看到的是凶手
And the last thing he saw was his killer.
我们不知道他的姓名和年龄
We don't know his name or age,
但我们估计是10至12岁
but we're estimating between 10 and 12 years old.
他棕色头发和淡褐色眼睛  最后看见时
He has brown hair, hazel eyes, and was last seen
身穿短裤  运动鞋和灰白夹克
wearing shorts, sneakers, and a gray and white jacket.
我们的绑匪是名男性  棕色头发
Now our kidnapper is male, brown hair,
身高175至180
between 5'10" and 6".
他携带一支格洛克45口径手枪
He was carrying a Glock .45,
和我们在被害人身上发现的
which matches the size of the slugs
子弹口径相吻合
that we found in our victim's body.
两张照片上都有时间显示
Now both photos have time stamps on them,
因此诱拐案发生在周二晚上12点
so we know that the abduction took place 12 pm on Tuesday.
48小时后  被绑儿童生还的机会
After 48 hours, the chances of finding a child abduction
很小很小
victim alive go way down.
最重要的是找到那个孩子
The only thing that matters is finding that kid.
如果他失踪了36小时
If he's been missing for 36 hours,
为什么他的父母还不来报案
how come his parents haven't reported it?
他们可能不知道
They might not know.
也许他们在别人挟持下
Or they might be under duress.
他身穿短裤
He was wearing shorts,
很可能意味着他知道自已要去公园
which probably means he knew he was going to the park.
如果他不是被诱骗的
Well, if he wasn't lured there,
也许他认识绑匪
maybe he knew his kidnapper.
但为什么绑匪需要枪呢
But then why would the kidnapper need a gun?
我给纽约州警察和假释部门电邮了照片
I e-mailed the photo to the New York state police
他们正在调查
and the parole division. They're looking into
与这起绑架案手法相似的绑匪资料
any kidnappers with this abduction M.O.
埃斯波西托正在公园里
And Esposito is canvassing that part of the park
寻找目击证人
looking for any witnesses.
学校那边有什么消息
Well, what about schools?
如果这孩子上的是当地学校
If the boy goes to a local school,
他们会知道他缺席了
they'd know he was absent.
让警员把他的照片
Have uniforms fax his photo to
-传真给5个区内所有的学校  -收到
- all schools in the five boroughs. - Done.
那辆车看起来像小型或超小型汽车
That car looks to be, like, a compact or a subcompact.
我们能判断出厂牌或是车型吗
Can we get the make or model?
实验室已经在调查了
Lab's already looking into it.
我们把周二晚上进出公园
We're pulling video from all traffic cameras on the streets
所有街边的交通录像都调出来
leading in and out of the park on Tuesday evening.
-也许有拍到车牌  -或司机的样子
- Maybe we'll catch a license plate. - Or the driver's face.
要是我们放大相片的这一小块怎样
What if we were to enlarge this part of the photo--
不包括人脸  仅是车窗这块
not the face, just this part of the window?
你觉得玻璃映出了司机的样子
Are you thinking of the reflection?
我在想  也许我们能通过后视镜看到
I'm wondering if maybe we can see the kidnapper's face
-绑匪的样子  -值得一试
- in that side view mirror. - It's worth a shot.
请马上派鉴证组图像处理技术员过来
I need a C.S.U. photo tech up here now.
你确定你没见过他
You sure you haven't seen him?
老兄  我每天都能看到一堆小孩
Man, I see so many kids every day,
但根本分不清谁跟谁
I couldn't tell one from the next.
那在同一时间
What about a blue car
你有在这附近见过一部蓝色小车吗
around the same time, somewhere in this area?
-周二下午5点吗  -对
- Tuesday about 5:00? - Yeah.
-有啊  那是一辆蓝色的土星车  -确定吗
- Yeah, as a matter of fact, a blue saturn. - You sure?
当然  人我记不住
Yeah. People I forget.
但妨碍我做生意的车我可记忆犹新
Things that get in my way, I remember.
它就停在我地盘的前面
It was parked right in front of my regular spot.
结果我只好把摊摆在马路旁
Instead, I gotta set up at the edge of the roadway.
-害我差点被的士撞倒  -车里有人吗
- I almost get clipped by a cab. - Anybody inside?
没有  不然我肯定会骂他祖宗
No, because I woulda yelled at the driver if there was.
我真搞不懂这城市的人有啥毛病
I don't know what's wrong with people in this city.
-谢了  -不用
- Yeah, thanks. - Yeah.
咸酥饼小贩认出了绑匪的车
Our pretzel vendor I.D.'ed the kidnapper's car
是一辆蓝色土星轿车  年份是97年到02年
as a blue saturn sedan, anywhere from '97 to '02.
问题是
The problem is,
单是一个三州区就登记了
there are 6,000 blue saturns registered
6千辆蓝色土星车
in the tristate area alone.
莱恩  交通监控摄像查得怎样了
Ryan, where are we on the traffic cams?
要是有厂牌和型号就能缩小范围
The make and model will help narrow it down,
但现在录像还是很多
but there's a lot of footage.
另外  学校没有对缺勤建立中心数据库
There's also no central database for school absences.
我们无法按年级或性别检索
We can't sort by grade or gender,
而且最近在流行重感冒
and there's a bad cold making the rounds,
学校比平常多了学生缺席
so more kids are out than usual.
那州警那边有消息吗
What about state police?
没有  也没有查到
Whole lot of nada, and nothing popped
绑架手法相似的假释犯
on parolees with the same kidnapping MO.
好的  我会继续等着
Yes, I'll continue to hold.
-警探  相片放大过了  -谢谢
- Detective, enhanced and enlarged. - Thank you.
什么  放大
Oh, the enhancement
不过就是增强了原图的像素而已
only increased the pixilation on all these.
上面连后视镜都看不到
You can't even see there's a side view mirror.
卡塞尔  这可不像在《24小时》
Well, it's not like on "24," Castle.
在现实中
In the real world,
变焦和放大只能做到这样
zoom and enhance can only get us so far.
但也不至于...
Yeah, but you can't even--
根本没有映像  一片模糊
There's no reflection. It's just mush.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
还行
Yeah.
骗你的  天啊  这孩子只小阿丽克西斯几岁
No. God, this kid isn't that much younger than Alexis.
别担心  我们会找到他的
Don't worry. We'll find him.
阿丽克西斯
Alexis.
-怎么了  -这我见过
- What? - I've seen this before.
-你见过什么  -他袜子上的污迹
- You've seen what? - This mark on his sock.
阿丽克西斯踢足球时
Alexis used to get these
总会沾上这种污迹
when she played soccer.
这是别的孩子
They're cleat marks from where
踢她小腿时留下的球鞋钉印
other kids kick her in the shin.
如果他当时正在公园踢足球
If he was playing soccer in the park,
他有可能是某个球队或社团的成员
he might be a part of an organized team or a league.
青年团有官方网址可供搜索
And youth leagues have web sites that you can go to.
父母和孩子可上网查看分数和名次
The parents and kids can track scores and standings.
我跟社团理事谈过
I spoke to the league commissioner,
他说只有一支年龄由10岁至12岁的球队
and only one 10- to 12-year-old team
在周二练习
practiced on Tuesday--
野猫队
The wildcats.
这个
There!
泰勒·多尼哥
Tyler Donegal.
今年12岁
He's 12.
莱恩  马上对这孩子展开搜救工作
Ryan, let's get everything we can on this kid.
时间不多了  我们得安全救出他
The clock is ticking, and we gotta bring him back alive.
泰勒·多尼哥和母亲住在韦斯切斯特
Tyler Donegal lives with his mother in Westchester.
法庭记录显示他的父母
Court records show that parents divorced
于2个月前正式离婚
finalized two months ago.
联系他的父母没
You reach the parents?
刚联系上他的母亲马瑞尔·莱科特
Just got off with the mother-- Mirielle Lefcourt.
她去年搬出纽约市区了
She moved out of the city last year.
上个月刚和一位麻醉师结婚
Got remarried to an anesthesiologist last month.
她说她完全不知道儿子失踪了
She says she has no idea that her son is missing.
儿子这两天正和前夫待在城里
He was spending two days in the city with her ex.
她现在正在赶来
She's on her way in now.
如果父亲有探视权  那他到底去哪了
If the father had custody, where the hell is he,
他又为何不报案呢
and why didn't he report the boy missing?
头儿  我们正在查
We're working on that, sir.
他父亲是西百老汇街和运河街一带
The father's a maintenance supervisor at high-rise
高层住宅的维修主管
on West Broadway and Canal.
住所离中央公园就6个街口
He lives six blocks from central park.
多尼哥昨今两天都打给公司请病假了
Donegal called in sick for work yesterday and today.
父母离婚  独子  母亲迅速再婚
Divorced parents, one child, one spouse remarries quickly?
所以说她为了嫁住郊区豪宅的医生
So she dumps the janitor in the city
-抛弃了城里的丈夫  -害得父子分离
- for the doctor in the burbs. - All the father has left his son.
以上一切符合诱拐监护人子女的特征
It's got all the hallmarks of a custodial abduction.
你拿到照片了吗
You got a photo?
我这就去拿
I'll get one.
迪恩·多尼哥
Dean Donegal.
身高180  体重160斤
5'10", 175...
-褐发  -主要特征吻合
- Brown hair. - Well, the vitals match.
但他为何要持枪挟持自己的儿子呢
Yeah, but why do you need a gun to kidnap your own son?
他只需要让他上车
You just put him in the car,
告诉他去吃雪糕就好了
tell him you're going for ice cream.
-他这是为何  -贝克特  母亲来了
- What's he doing? - Hey, beckett, the mother's here.
好  莱恩  你去迪恩的办公室一趟
All right, Ryan, you go to Dean's office.
埃斯波西托  你去他的公寓看看
Esposito, you check out his apartment.
-也许这家人还发生了别的事  -好的
- Maybe something else is going on with that family. - Right.
我儿子在哪里
Where's my son?
莱科特女士  我们正努力在找
That's what we're trying to determine, Mrs. Lefcourt.
你最后一次和你儿子讲话是什么时候
When was the last time that you spoke with him?
两天前  我把他送到他爸爸家时
Uh, two days ago when I dropped him off at his father's.
他应该跟迪恩在一起  你们问过迪恩了吗
He was supposed to be with Dean. Have you talked to Dean?
我们正在努力找他
We're trying to locate him now.
他没在上班吗  他从不缺勤
He's not at work? He never misses work.
你能说说离婚的事吗
Can you tell me about the divorce?
迪恩对此是什么态度
How did Dean take that?
不太好  他很痛苦很生气
Um, not well. He was very bitter and angry.
他有枪吗
Does he own a gun?
有把手枪
A handgun.
因为他的大楼曾遭盗窃
Yes. There were break-ins in his building.
你知道枪的类型吗
Do you know what kind?
你问我枪的事干什么呢
Why are you asking me about a-a gun?
有人中枪了吗  难道是我儿子吗
Was somebody shot? Was my son shot?
不  没人中枪  莱科特女士
No, nobody was shot, Mrs. Lefcourt.
只是挟持你儿子的人手上有把枪
It's just, the man who took your son was carrying a gun.
现在要给你看一张图片
Now I'm gonna have to show you this photograph.
你认识这个男人吗
Do you recognize this man?
我不知道  是迪恩吗
I don't know. Is that Dean?
我指望你能告诉我答案
I was hoping that you could tell me.
你认得这辆车吗  是你前夫的吗
What about this car? Is that his car?
不  迪恩没车  要用的时候才会租
No, Dean doesn't own a car. He-- he rents one as he needs one.
是格洛克
A Glock.
迪恩那把是格洛克手枪
Dean's gun, it's a Glock.
离婚的时候我们要详细列举双方的财产
We had to itemize our property for the divorce.
莱科特女士  迪恩有喜欢
Mrs. Lefcourt, does Dean have a place
带泰勒去的地方吗
that he likes to take Tyler?
比如常去的游乐场之类的
Any, um, favorite hangouts?
没有  据我所知  他从没带他去过哪里
No, as far as I know, he's never taken him anywhere.
不是这样的
That's not true.
迪恩家人在波可诺斯有一间房子
Dean's family has a cabin in the Poconos.
宾夕法尼亚州警正赶往那处房子
Pennsylvania state police are on their way to the cabin.
好运的话  就能顺利找到泰勒
With any luck, we'll find Tyler.
你没事吧
You okay?
真不敢想象泰勒母亲的心情
I can't imagine how Tyler's mother feels.
对啊  我也是
Yeah, me neither.
阿丽克西斯四岁时  我们一起去白原市的
When Alexis was 4, we went christmas shopping
商场做圣诞采购
at some mall in--in white plains.
我正在试戴深灰色的软毡帽
I was trying on some charcoal fedora.
一回头  发现她人不见了
I turn around, she is gone, vanished.
我四处寻找  跟商场保安
I looked everywhere, so did mall security,
和警察一块
so did the police.
我们足足找了一个小时
We searched for an hour.
用不着当小说家
You don't have to be a novelist
也能想象出所有最坏的情况
to think of all the worst-case scenarios.
后来你在哪里找到她呢
Where'd you find her?
一架子冬季外套后面  她觉得无聊
Behind a rack of winter coats. She got bored.
就爬进那底下睡觉去了
She crawled underneath there and went to sleep.
直到今天  我还会梦到这事
To this day, I still dream about that.
刚跟埃斯波西托聊完  看来迪恩跑路了
Just got off with Esposito. Looks like Dean's on the move.
他们找到了什么
What did they find?
他们就是什么都没找到
It's what they didn't find--
浴室没牙刷  没除臭剂
no toothbrush, no deodorant,
也没沐浴液
no shampoo in the shower.
我这就查他的信用卡
I'll run his credit card
看看他是否真的出游了
for anything that indicates he's traveling.
这就是迪恩的办公桌吗
Dean's desk?
很难忽略对吧  贴满了照片
You can't miss it, right? Pictures everywhere.
他称之为泰勒嘉年华
He calls it Tyler-palooza.
他只在这里工作吗
Is this his only work area?
是的  没错
Yeah. Uh-huh.
他请病假的时候听起来怎么样
How'd he sound when he called in sick?
他听上去  紧张吗
Did he sound... Stressed?
说实话  警探  迪恩没有打来请假
Tell you the truth, detective, Dean didn't call in sick.
-我替他找了个借口  -为什么
- I covered for him. - Why?
他的前妻在正式离婚后五分钟
His ex-wife got remarried to some rich doctor
就跑去跟有钱的医生结婚了
like five minutes after the divorce was final.
他欠了一屁股债
He had legal bills up the ass.
我想他只是想多陪伴自己的儿子
I figured, he just needed to spend a little time with his son.
所以即使他没打电话
So what if he didn't call in sick?
我也会挺他  这是我们这里的做法
I had his back. That's how we do it down here.
嘿  特丽萨
hey, Teresa!
好的  来了
All right, already.
哇呜
Whoa.
印第安纳有什么  迪恩
What's in Indy, Dean?
或许他有家人在印第安纳波利斯
Maybe he's got family in Indianapolis,
可以信任的朋友让他匿藏起来
friends he can trust, someone who can hide him.
是的  但没有任何机票
Yeah, but there weren't any airline tickets
是用他或者泰勒的名字买的
purchased in his name or in Tyler's.
小木屋里没人
Yo, the cabin's empty.
当地警局说看起来
P.A. State troopers say it looks like
那地方已经空置好几个月了
there hasn't been anybody there in months.
迪恩·多尼哥的财务报告有发现了
We just got a hit on Dean Donegal's financials.
一小时前  他订了皇后区的一间旅店房间
An hour ago, he booked a motel room in Jamaica, Queens.
那距离机场不远
That's not far from the airport.
他可能还在企图带走泰勒
He might still be trying to get Tyler out of town.
-那就太好了  -他杀了人
- If we're lucky. - He shot someone,
他在潜逃  他现在极度不稳定
He's on the run, he's under extreme duress.
我们得在事情变得血腥前逮捕他
Let's get him before this ends bloody for everyone.
纽约警局
NYPD!
泰勒  泰勒  你在吗
Tyler! Tyler, you here?!
-举手  举起你的手  -泰勒
- Hands! Show me your hands! - Tyler!
-浴室安全  -他不在这里
- Bathroom's clear. - He's not here.
泰勒在哪里
Where's Tyler?
我不知道  他们叫我住进旅馆
I don't know. They told me to check into a motel
-等待下一步指示  -谁指使你
- and wait for further instructions. - Who did?
我不晓得  我只知道他们劫走了他
I don't know. All I know is, they took him.
如果我帮你们  他们会杀了我儿子
And if I help you, they'll kill my son.
他在哪  迪恩
Where is Tyler, Dean?
我说了  我不知道
I told you, I don't know.
你为什么要去印第安纳波利斯
Why were you going to Indianapolis?
印第安纳  你在说什么
Indian, what are you talking about?
我们知道你在查机票价格
We know you were checking on airfares.
我在找假期旅游的资料
I was researching a trip for the holidays.
什么  你以为我绑架了自己的儿子吗
What, you think I took my own son?
你住在机场旁的酒店里
You were in a hotel by the airport.
-是他们叫我去那里的  -谁
- That's where they told me to go. - Who?
拜托了  他们说如果我报警他就死定了
Please. They said, if I talk to the cops, he's dead.
迪恩  要是你的儿子有危险
Dean, if you're son is in danger,
你必须告诉我们所有事情
Then you need to tell us what you know.
我在他训练后去接他回家
I went to pick him up after practice.
他并不在那里
When he wasn't at the usual spot,
我就以为他自己回去了
I figured he must have walked home.
当我回到家时  那部手机在门垫上
When I got back to my apartment, that phone was on my doormat.
里面有条短信
It had a text on it.
我们劫走了你的儿子  别告诉任何人
"We have your son. Tell no one.
只能使用这个电话
Use only this phone."
报警的话泰勒就死定了
Contact the police, and Tyler dies."
准备好  我们会告诉你该怎么做
"Stand by. We will tell you where to go and what to do.
不许告诉别人  你儿子的小命就看你表现了
Tell no one. Your son's life depends on it."
-他们想要什么  -我完全不晓得
- What do they want from you? - I have no idea.
迪恩的格洛克手枪是九毫米口径
Dean's glock is a 9 millimeter.
相同牌子  不同型号
Right make, wrong model.
灯泡雷恩是被点45口径的枪射杀
Lightbulb Len was killed with a .45.
那手机里的是一次性电话卡
The sim card from his cell phone is a burner,
而且里面的信息不是由别的手机发来的
and the text messages aren't coming from another phone.
是从网络信息服务发来
They're coming from an internet texting service
总部在乌克兰  没有IP地址  无法追踪
based in the Ukraine, no I.P. Address, untraceable.
查查电话卡  我要所有手机短信的影印本
Track the sim. I want a printout of every text message.
拿到那手机的电子序列号码
And get the electronic serial number off that phone.
我要查出购买地点
I want to find out where
-还有是谁买的  -没问题  长官
- it was purchased and by whom. - You got it, sir.
他们想从你那儿得到什么
What do they want from you?
-要赎金吗  -你在开玩笑吗
- Are they after a ransom? - Are you kidding.
我离婚后欠了四万美金债务
I'm 40 grand in debt after my divorce.
我快破产了
I'm looking up at broke.
你前妻的新丈夫呢  他很有钱
What about your ex-wife's new husband? He has money.
他们没联络他  他们找的是我
They're not calling him. They're calling me.
要是他们知道我在这里怎么办
What if they find out I'm here?
我只想儿子平安回来
I just want my son back.
那么你最好的选择就是跟我们合作
Then your best option is to work with us.
我们会帮你的
Let us help you.
我需要些新鲜空气
I need to get some air.
我知道这很难
Look, I know that this is hard.
但你必须相信我们  我们会找到他的
But you have to trust us. We will find him.
好吧
Okay.
别让他们伤害我的孩子
Don't let 'em hurt my boy.
他在哪里  泰勒在哪
Where is he? Where is Tyler?
你应该在足球训练后接他
You should've been there to pick him
-回家的  -我们在尽力做能做的事
- up at soccer practice! - We're doing everything we can.
这就是为什么我不应该答应
This is why I should've never
-共同监护权  -一切都会没事的
- agreed to joint custody. - It's gonna be all right.
你别插手  你不是这个家的人
Stay outta this. You're not family.
-他也是我的儿子  -坐下
- He's my boy, too! - Sit down!
够了
That's enough!
现在我要所有人冷静下来  好好合作
Now I need everyone to calm down, cooperate, and think.
迪恩  你注意到有不寻常的人在你儿子身边吗
Dean, you notice anyone unusual hanging around your son,
他最近有发生任何异常的事吗
Anything out of the ordinary going on in his life?
不  我是说  我不觉得
No. I mean, I... I don't think so.
那你们两个呢
What about you two?
-什么都没想起  -没有
- Nothing comes to mind. - No.
这起绑架显然是精心策划的
Now this abduction was clearly planned.
绑匪得知道泰勒的作息
So the kidnapper had to know where Tyler was gonna be.
长官  这是从绑匪发来的信息
Sir, this is a message. It's from the kidnapper.
带有一段录像
There's a video attached.
嗨  老爸
Hi, dad.
我知道你很担心  但我没事
I know you're worried, but I'm okay.
他们说只要你乖乖听他们的话去做
They say if you do what they ask,
就会没事的
everything will be fine.
千万别报警
Just don't go to the police.
我很快会见到你
I'll see you soon,
还有别忘了喂艾斯
and don't forget to feed Ace.
感谢老天他还活着
Oh, thank god he's alive.
这儿有摄影时间  凌晨一点三十一分
There's a time stamp on it, 1:31 am.
在八分钟前拍摄的
That was sent eight minutes ago.
这是好事  莱科特先生
It's a good thing, Mrs. Lefcourt.
这是证明他活着的录像
It's called a proof of life video.
绑匪发来证明你儿子还活着
The kidnapper sent it to prove your son's alive,
然后要你做他们要求的事
and that you do exactly what they ask.
好的  你要完全按照他们的指示去做
Okay. You will do exactly what they ask you to.
-明白吗  -等等  最后那段再播一次
- Do you understand? - Wait. Play that last part again.
别忘了喂艾斯
Don't forget to feed Ace.
艾斯是谁  我不认识什么艾斯
Who's Ace? I don't know any Ace.
-我们没养宠物  -他想告诉我们些信息
- We don't have any pets. - He's sending us a message.
他是个聪明的孩子
He's a smart boy.
艾斯可能代表某人或者一项工作
Uh, Ace could refer to a person or a business.
长官  又收到一则短信
Sir, there's another text.
三十分钟后  运河街680号
"680 canal street. 30 minutes."
那是我工作的地方
That's the building where I work.
那是什么地方  珠宝店  银行吗
What's there, a jewelry store, a bank?
-不  只是办公室  -为什么要你
- No, just offices. - Well, why you?
那栋大厦有什么特别的地方令他们需要你
What's so special about that building that they need you?
噢  我的天
Oh, god.
因为我有电梯使用权
Because I have elevator access
可以到达那栋大厦的所有楼层
to all the floors in the building.
你是人体钥匙
You're a human key.
长官  我刚和大厦业主沟通过了
Sir, I just talked to the building's owner.
他正将大厦蓝图和大厦的承租人名单发过来
He's e-mailing blueprints and a tenant list for 680 canal,
-包括了有保安的楼层  -莱恩和埃斯波西托
-including the secure floors. - Ryan and Esposito
跟我行动  我们送迪恩到大厦
are with me. We'll take Dean to the building.
我安排紧急救援小组做好准备  以防不测
I've arranged to have an E.S.U team standing by in striking distance.
长官  你不能让迪恩进大厦
Sir, you can't take Dean to that building.
-这太危险了  -他是个深爱儿子的父亲
- It is way too dangerous. - He's a father who loves his son.
你不可能阻止他的
You're not gonna be able to stop him.
在找到那男孩之前  我们没有其他选择
And until we find the boy, we don't have any other choice.
彻查那段录像
Scrub the video.
-找到任何有用的线索  -遵命  长官
- Look for anything that could lead us to him. - Yes, sir.
好的  我们就在一个街区外
All right. We're a block away.
我们能看到和听见
We'll be able to see and hear
你那儿发生的任何事  好吗
everything that's happening, okay?
另外我们克隆了你的手机
And we cloned your phone
这样我们就能同步收到你的信息
so we'll be able to read your texts in real time.
你按照绑匪信息里的指示去做
You follow the kidnapper's instructions to the letter.
-别逞英雄  你懂了吗  -是的
- No cowboy stuff, you understand me? - Yes.
嗨  老爸
Hi, dad.
我知道你很担心  但我没事
I know you're worried, but I'm okay.
他们说只要你乖乖听他们的话去做
They say if you do what they ask,
就会没事的
everything will be fine.
千万别报警
Just don't go to the police.
晚点见  别忘了喂艾斯
I'll see you soon, and don't forget to feed Ace.
背景没有任何可辨别的东西
There are no identifying markers in the background.
就是一片黑
It's all black.
我不知道我们能不能及时找到他
I don't know if we're gonna find him in time.
视频是在凌晨一点三十一分拍的
The video was taken at 1:31 a.m.
但是一直到一点三十九分才发出去
But they didn't send it till 1:39.
有的时候信息发出去了以后  要过一会儿
Yeah, well, sometimes it takes a while
-才能接收到  -但是相差八分钟吗
- for a text to go through.  - Yeah, but eight minutes?
你想让迪恩帮你做件事
You want Dean to do something for you.
所以你拍了证明这个人质还活着的视频
You make a proof of life video.
但却等了八分钟才把它发出去  为什么呢
But you wait eight minutes to send it. Why?
也许是没信号  或是信号不足
Well, maybe there wasn't a signal or not enough bars.
也许他们得走到很远的地方才有信号
Yeah. Maybe they had to walk a long way to get a signal.
也许他们是在
Maybe they were under a...
地下
underground.
艾斯
"Ace".
艾斯不是人名
It's not "Ace".
而是字母a  c和e
It's a-c-e --
是指a  c  e号地铁线
The a, c, and e subway lines.
他们把Tyler囚禁在地铁站里
They're holding Tyler in the subway.
他肯定是看到了路标
He must have spotted a sign.
a  c  e号线上有太多地铁站了
There's half a dozen stations where the a, c, and e stop.
我们搜不过来的
That's too many to search.
没错  但是三条线的终点站
Yeah, but the last stop for all three lines
都在运河街和西百老汇街的交界处
is on Canal Street and West Broadway.
-那就在  -迪恩工作那栋楼的楼下
- That's --  - Right under Dean's building.
-他们把他藏在大家的眼皮底下  -我们走
- They've been holding him under everyone's nose. - Let's go.
搜查站台东面的每个房间
Check every room on the east end of the station.
你们几个去搜站台两边的售票厅  快去
You guys, check ticket booths on both ends. Go.
-好的  -收到
- Right.  - Got it.
卡塞尔  你在想什么
Castle, what are you thinking?
把他关在这的唯一原因就是为了逃跑方便
The only reason to keep him here is for a quick getaway,
这里的便利条件就在于运河街680号
which is helped by the fact that 680 Canal Street
有独立的地铁入口
has its own entrance to the subway.
要是我的话  我就会选在一个
If it were me...I'd keep close enough
可以跟我的同伙保持联系
to hook up with my partners
却又不会碍事的地方
but far enough that I would be out of the way.
也就是说他把泰勒关在
Which means he's holding Tyler
隧道的西端
on the west end of the tunnel.
隧道西端吗  这个房间
West end of the tunnel? This room.
-好的  你在这等着  -没门儿
- All right. You should stay back.  - No chance.
现在去三十七楼
"Go to the 37th floor now".
他们之前说三十分钟的
They said 30 minutes.
现在还没到三十分钟呢
It hasn't been 30 minutes yet.
他们在更改时间
They're changing the timetable
防止你去报警
in case you went to the cops.
三十七楼上有什么
What's on the 37th floor?
什么都没有  那层楼是空置的
Nothing. It's vacant.
连保安的没有
It's not even secure.
打给贝克特
Try Beckett.
没人
Nothing.
直接转到留言信箱了
It's going straight to voice mail.
-她肯定已经下地铁站了  -我得走了
- She must already be in the subway.  - I gotta go.
记住  我们看得见也听得见你的一切行为
Remember, we can see and hear everything.
一旦发生任何紧急情况
Anything goes south,
马上就会有一百名警察冲进去的
a hundred cops will be on you inside a minute.
找到我儿子之前不许有警察出现
Not until you find my son.
是我倒霉
Just my luck.
这么晚还得来加班
Pulled graveyard tonight.
好的  他进去了
All right. He's in.
他跟保安表现得挺自然的  他没事
Not bad with the guard. Guy's all right.
摄像头和麦克风都好用
Camera and mic are all good.
-带我们到三十九楼  -我要先见泰勒
- Take us to the 39th floor.  - I want to see Tyler first.
乖乖听话  你很快就会见到他的
Just follow instructions. You'll see him soon enough.
三十九楼有什么
What's on the 39th floor?
一间金融公司  布瑞金&怀特
A financial firm -- Breskin & Wright.
三十七楼只是个幌子
37 was just a staging area.
他们没有蒙面  也就是说他们一旦
They let him see their faces. As soon as they get
达到目的以后  就会杀了他
what they came for, they're gonna kill him.
就像灯泡雷恩一样
Just like Lightbulb Len.
贝克特的电话还是转到语言信箱  卡塞尔的也是
Beckett's still going to voice mail. Castle, too.
头  下一步怎么办
Sir...what do you want to do?
要是我们在找到那个孩子之前冲进去
If we go in before we find the kid,
我们可能会害死他们两个
we might lose 'em both.
一名持械绑匪  还有那个孩子
One armed and the kid.
如果我冲进去的话
If I go in, he'll kill him
在我开枪之前他就会杀了那个孩子
before I get a shot off.
他拿着个手电筒
He's holding a flashlight.
如果我们把周围的灯都关了
If we kill the ambient light,
他就会成为唯一的光源
he'll light up like a Christmas tree.
我们只要
We just...
看来这是注定的了
It's like it's meant to be.
也许雷恩可以避免另一场悲剧
Maybe Lenny can prevent another tragedy.
听我数
On my count.
三  二
Three, two...
一
one.
按负一楼  下地铁站
Hit p-1. The subway.
我都按你说的做了  泰勒人呢
I did what you asked. Now where's Tyler?
你一会就会见到他了
You'll see him in a minute.
对不起了  迪恩
Sorry, Dean.
这是你的最后一站
Last stop.
大堂
Lobby.
我们应该到地铁站那层的
We're supposed to go to subway level.
为什么在大堂停了
Why are we stopping at the lobby?
别看我
Don't look at me.
没错  看我吧
No, look at me.
我建议你们放下武器
I suggest you drop your weapons.
泰勒在哪
Where's Tyler?
罪魁祸首是罗伯特·金凯德
The ringleader was Robert Kincaid...
前任的证券交易员
former bond trader.
他策划了整个行动
He's the one who planned the entire operation.
经济虽然崩盘了
The economy might have collapsed,
但他还是想要捞一笔
but he was still gonna get his payday.
他们大多数都是以前的华尔街大亨
Most of them were ex wall streeters.
他们知道要是没有开门人的话
They knew that they needed a biometric clearance in order
他们是去不了安保楼层的
to get on secure floors,
而且他们也知道迪恩不会帮他们的
and they knew that Dean wasn't gonna help them,
所以他们就抓了泰勒作为筹码
so they took Tyler as leverage.
但是他们偷的只是一些文件而已
But all they took were files.
那是财务文件  包括未公布的收益报表
Financial files, containing unpublished earnings reports.
对明智的投资者来说  这些文件值上百万
To a savvy investor, they'd be worth millions.
要是灯泡雷恩没在公园里
Would've worked, too, if Lightbulb Len hadn't have been
拍到那些照片的话  计划本来是会成功的
taking pictures in the park.
他帮我们抓到了杀他自己的凶手
He helped catch his own killer.
还制止了一起绑架案
And foiled a kidnapping.
这还真是有诗意
It's kind of poetic...
当然是难以形容的悲剧诗意啦
in an unspeakably tragic sort of way.
你在地铁站里打伤的那个家伙
The guy you shot in the subway?
金凯德雇来的那个恶棍
The thug Kincaid hired to do his dirty work.
已经供认了绑架泰勒
He just confessed to kidnapping Tyler,
和杀害灯泡雷恩的罪行  而且不出所料
murdering Lightbulb Len, and no surprise,
他不到两秒钟就把金凯德供出来了
he ratted out Kincaid in two seconds flat.
说到招供[和老鼠同形异义]
Oh. Speaking of rats...
我得  我得走了
I-I gotta -- I gotta go.
我是全世界最差劲的人了
I'm the worst person in the whole world.
不是的
No, you're not.
你很棒  而且你很善良
You're wonderful, and you're kind,
还很贴心
and you're sweet.
我是老鼠杀手
I'm a rat killer.
这可说不准  它不一定死了呀
You don't know that.
你顶多算是"丢人"[loser有失败者的意思]
You may just be a loser.
我是说丢老鼠的人  听起来还真别扭
A-a rat loser. This did not come out right.
听着
Look...
如果他在乎你  他会理解你的
if he cares, he'll understand.
是呀  他理解我倒是没问题
Yeah, he'll understand, all right.
但是当他在学校里见到我  他就会想
When he sees me in the halls at school, he'll think,
这就是那个把我的死党弄丢了的女生
there's the awful girl that lost my best friend.
他来了
It's him.
我想你了
Hi. I missed you.
我也是
I missed you, too.
怎么了
W-what's wrong?
西奥多出事了
It's about Theodore.
肯定是我喂他的时候他从笼子里跑出去了
When I fed him, he must have got out of his cage, and...
-然后就不见了  -他不见了
- and he's gone.  - He's gone?
我们到处都找过了  我发誓
We looked everywhere. I swear.
我们把整个地方都翻了个底朝天
We've turned this whole place upside down.
他怎么跑出去的
How'd he get out?
我肯定是没把笼子锁好
I must not have locked the cage right.
阿什利  我很抱歉
Ashley, I'm so sorry.
你完全可以恨我
You have every right to hate me.
别这么说  阿丽克西斯  我
Come on, Alexis. I...
我是很难过  但是我不恨你
I'm -- I'm upset, but I don't hate you.
你不恨我吗
You don't?
真的不恨  你看看你把这个地方翻的
I mean, no, look at this place.
看看你多努力想要把他找回来
Look at what you did to try to get him back.
还有谁会这么做
Who else would do that?
可是你很在乎他
You cared about him a lot.
是的  但是
Yeah, but...
我更在乎你
I care about you more.
找到他了
Found him.